https://arancrafts.com/aeu-legal-privacy/

Aran Crafts Irish Aran Knitwear
Home / Privacy
Privacy Policy
West End Knitwear Limited respects your right to privacy. As part of the operations of the arancrafts.com web site we will retain certain information including your name, address, phone numbers, e-mail address, IP address, billing address and shipping address and product selection. This information will be retained in accordance with our obligations under the Irish Data Protection Act 1988.We are committed to protecting and respecting the privacy of your personal data. This update to our privacy policy explains how your data is collected, transferred and disclosed by West End Knitwear Ltd (arancrafts.com)The Data we collectPersonal Data-The personal data means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. The personal data we collect – such as First name, last name, title, email address, billing address, delivery address, telephone number.Transaction data – such as details of your purchases and fulfilment of your orders such as order number, product number, number of items, currency, discounts, price, payment method etc.Financial Data – For Payment of purchases and to give refunds – Payments accepted by Credit Card and PayPal are collected, processed and secured through Braintree and PayPal Inc,Technical & Usage Data – such as details of device(s) you use to access our services, IP address, login data, username, browser type, version, location, operating type and platform, website performance statistics, traffic and other communication data.Aggregated Data – We also collect and use aggregated data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated data is not considered personal data as it does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For e.g we may use this data to calculate percentage of users from a certain country, sales, traffic pattern and related site information but these statistics will include no personally identifying information.Marketing Data – such as your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties.How we collect the dataWe may collect data in the following ways, by direct interactions by filling in forms, entering information online, email, post, by telephone, marketing, creating an account, purchase on our website, subscribe to our newsletter, enter competitions, user cookies.How we keep your data safeWe have appropriate organisational safeguards and security measures in place to insure your information is secure to protect your data from being lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way. We encrypt our online data and it is stored on secure servers and hidden behind a firewall.We require any third party who is contracted to process your personal data on our behalf to have security measures in place to protect your data and to treat such data in accordance with the law.Why we collect dataWe only collect and use your personal data for the following purposes:Fulfil your order(s), Meet our legal responsibilities, keep you up to date with the latest offers and trends, give you a better shopping experience and improve our services.How we use your information.We only collect and process your personal data when we have consent to do so or we need your personal data to perform a contract with you, for example fulfil orders, payments, customer support etc.To Create an account – The use of Personal Data name, address, phone number, email address, we do this to perform our contract with you when creating an account.To Process and Delivery your order – The use of Personal Data name & address, phone number, email address, financial data, transaction information – We do this to perform our contract with you to process and send your purchase and let you know it’s on its way.Sending you services messages by text or email such as order updates – We do this to inform you of your order updates and let you know when it is on its way.Internal record keeping – to meet our legal obligations and operational needsContact history what you have said to us by email for example – to provide customer service and support, we do this to perform our contract to you and provide the best service.To deliver relevant website content, online advertisements and information for you and to measure the effectiveness of the advertising provided – Necessary for our interests to grow our business and inform our marketing strategy.The use of Data analytics – To improve our website, products, services, marketing, customer experience, market research and statistical purposes, – The use of technical and usage data to keep our website updated and relevant to develop our business and marketing strategy.To administer, protect and improve our business and our website, including data analysis, testing, troubleshooting, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data, setting default option for you such as currency and language. – Necessary for running our business administration IT services, network security, and to detect and prevent fraud. Necessary to comply with legal obligations.Sending you information by email about our new products, services and special offers and discounts -To keep you up to date with offers and news, we will only send this information if you have signed up (opted in) for our Newsletter.To inform or remind you by email of any task carried out via our website which remains uncompleted, such as incomplete orders or abandoned carts. Necessary for our legitimate interests to improve shopping experience.Purchase History and saved items – What you have purchased or saved in your basket to allow us to provide customer service.Keeping your informationWe hold your information for as long as you have your account or as long is needed to be able to provide the services to you support related reporting and trend analysis only and to meet legal or regulatory requirements.Sharing informationWe do not, and will not, sell trade or rent any of your personal data to any third party. We may disclose your data with trusted third parties as an essential part of being able to provide our services to you. Companies such as payment service providers, delivery companies. Professional service providers, such as website hosts, website developers, the analysing of data, providing marketing assistance, advertising partners and for system maintenance and support who help run our business. Such companies and individuals will have access to personal information needed to perform these functions but may not use it for any other purposes and are required to process the data in accordance with the Irish Data Protection Act 1988.Marketing, adverts, cookiesWe may send you a promotional offer/discount offer with your order from time to time. We will only send newsletters to you if you have opted in to receive information on latest news specials and discounts from us.You can unsubscribe to our newsletter at any time by following the link in the footer of the newsletter or emailing us at sales@arancrafts.com asking to be unsubscribed from our newsletter list.We also from occasion use online digital marketing advertising, to keep you aware of what we’re up to and find our products. Like many companies we may target arancrafts banners to you when you use other websites and apps. We do this using Google’s remarketing technology, this allows us to display relevant ads to you based on visiting our website. This advertisement will be displayed using cookies. If you would prefer not to receive targeted advertisement you can deactivate cookies for these purposes by visiting www.google.com/settings/ad and social networks, such as Facebook custom audience service, this allows us to deliver our ad’s to our audience through Facebook.Our use of analytics and targeted advertising toolsWe use analytics and targeted advertising tools to display relevant website content on our website and online advertisements, we use tools such as Google Analytics to analyse to target and improve our marketing campaigns, marketing strategies and website content.Google will use analytics information to evaluate your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf.Google should not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites please visit: http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptoutWe also may also use tools provided by other third parties, such as Facebook to perform similar tasks. We use the Facebook pixel which is an analytics tool that allows advertisers to measure the effectiveness of advertising by understanding the actions people take on a website. Advertisers can use pixel data to make sure ads are being shown to the right people, build advertising audiences and unlock additional Facebook advertising tools. Facebook cookies are 3rd party cookies used to track website goal conversions and create (anonymised) lists of people that visited our website. If you wish to disable Facebook cookies on your browser, please visit http://www.aboutads.info/choices/.You can also opt out by using your Facebook account https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screenCookiesOur website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website and to keep track of your visits. They help us to provide you with the very best experience when you browse our website and to make improvements to our website. They also help us and our advertising networks to make advertising relevant to you and your interests. You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of our website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For detailed information on the cookies which we and our third-party providers use and the reasons why we use them, please refer to our Cookie Policy.Your Data and countries outside of EuropeThe personal data we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, destinations outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”) using legally-provided mechanisms to lawfully transfer data across borders. It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our service providers. We will take all steps necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy notice.Changes to Privacy PolicyBy using the arancrafts.com web site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by West End Knitwear Limited. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it.Your RightsUnder the data privacy legislationYou have a right to obtain a copy of your personal data we hold, personal information about you and if so what that information is used for and why we hold it.You have the right to correct or update any personal data by contacting us on sales@arancrafts.com or logging into you’re your account (if applicable) and amending your data information.Request erasure of your personal information. This enables you to ask us to delete your personal data where there is no good reason for us to keep it.To restrict the processing of your information including automated decision making.Object to direct marketing.If you want to exercise any of these rights, then please email sales@arancrafts.comContact us:Please send any questions comments or requests to sales@arancrafts.comThis privacy notice was last updated on 15th May 2018
Irish Knitwear
Merino wool or pure new wool
Easy 30 days returns
30 days money back guarantee
100% Secure Checkout
PayPal / MasterCard / Visa
Contact Us Address: Monasterevan, Co. Kildare, Ireland.
Tel (USA / Canada):
011353 45 525319
Tel (Rest of World):
+353 45 525319
Email: sales@arancrafts.com
Customer Service:
Monday - Thursday 9am-5pm (GMT)
Friday 9am - 4pm (GMT)
© 2020 Aran Crafts. All Rights Reserved | Web Development by Aura Internet
